In a short video, I'm going to
demonstrate how you can apply
some paragraph formatting to a
letter to enhance the appearance.
The example I'm going to use
as a document I've downloaded
from the vision2learn website.
The first thing I need to do
is I'm going to change the line
spacing so that the letter is
more evenly spaced over the page.
So once I've highlighted all of
the text, I will then go to the
line spacing icon and select 1.5.
I could try 2, but 1.5 looks about
right for this document and the content.
So once I've selected that, as you can
see that has spread the information
out over the page more evenly.
The second task would be to change the
alignment of the business address, which
should really be at the right hand side.
So again, I will highlight the address,
go back up to the paragraph section,
select the Align Right tool from the
bar, click on that and that will then
move the address over to the right.
The next formatting I want to apply
is to this block of text here, which
I think should be bullet pointed.
So again, I will highlight the text,
go back up to the paragraph section,
select the bullet icon and from the
dropdown select a simple bullet point.
The very last piece of formatting
that I will apply to the letter
is to add a border to the page.
Again, go back up to the paragraph
section, I will select the border icon
and the drop down beside it and from
the list, select borders and shading.
Once the borders and shading box
has come up, I will then select page
border and select a suitable style.
For this document, I'm going
to select a double line style.
I need to check here to make sure
that it's being applied to the
whole document and then select OK.
As you can see, that now makes the
letter look much more presentable.